[Sharp Blade in the Snow]
[نصل حاد في الثلج]
[Episode 14]
[الحلقة 14]
Stop right there.
توقف هنا.
What happened to your hand?
ماذا حدث ليدك؟
I was careless just now
كنت مهملاً للتو
and hit it on the stone steps.
واضربها على الدرجات الحجرية.
You're a grown man now
أنت رجل بالغ الآن
yet still so reckless.
ومع ذلك لا يزالون متهورين للغاية.
You can't even walk properly.
لا يمكنك حتى المشي بشكل صحيح.
How could you possibly serve as the Imperial Consort?
كيف يمكنكِ أن تشغلي منصب القرينة الإمبراطورية؟
You're so timid in front of the Queen,
أنت خجول جداً أمام الملكة،
afraid to even touch her fingertips.
كانت تخشى حتى لمس أطراف أصابعها.
How will you ever please her?
كيف سترضيها؟
If this continues,
إذا استمر هذا الوضع،
sooner or later those male concubines
عاجلاً أم آجلاً، هؤلاء المحظيات الذكور
will walk all over you.
سوف يدوسون عليك.
Enough, Mother!
كفى يا أمي!
What more do you want me to do?
ماذا تريدني أن أفعل أكثر من ذلك؟
Do you want me to be like
هل تريدني أن أكون مثلك؟
Xiao Ze,
شياو زي
flaunting myself all day
أتباهى بنفسي طوال اليوم
with seductive behavior?
بسلوك مغرٍ؟
Isn't my current state
أليس وضعي الحالي
miserable enough?
هل هذا بائس بما فيه الكفاية؟
How much more do you want me to debase myself?
إلى أي مدى تريدني أن أذل نفسي أكثر؟
You...
أنت...
Rest well.
استرح جيداً.
Keep the wound dry
حافظ على جفاف الجرح
to avoid scarring.
لتجنب الندوب.
I am an envoy from Xiqi.
أنا مبعوث من شي تشي.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
تحية طيبة يا صاحب الجلالة.
Xiqi has been gaining momentum lately.
اكتسبت شركة Xiqi زخماً كبيراً مؤخراً.
You've already conquered two cities.
لقد غزوت مدينتين بالفعل.
Envoy, what brings you
أيها المبعوث، ما الذي أتى بك؟
to Mocheng so suddenly?
إلى موتشنغ فجأة هكذا؟
Your Majesty, you're still young
جلالتك، ما زلت شاباً
and may not be aware.
وقد لا يكونون على دراية بذلك.
Prime Minister Bai should still remember
لا يزال على رئيس الوزراء باي أن يتذكر
the agreement between Xiqi and Mocheng from years ago.
الاتفاقية المبرمة بين شي تشي وموتشنغ قبل سنوات.
I just had a few words of argument with her
لقد تبادلت معها بضع كلمات من الجدال
and now she really wants to marry me off to Xiqi.
والآن هي تريد حقاً أن تزوجني من شيقي.
I've heard that the young master of Xiqi
سمعت أن السيد الشاب لـ Xiqi
has worn a mask since childhood due to illness.
يرتدي قناعاً منذ طفولته بسبب المرض.
No one has ever seen his face.
لم يرَ أحد وجهه قط.
He must be ugly.
لا بد أنه قبيح.
This isn't just a political marriage.
هذا ليس مجرد زواج سياسي.
This is clearly asking for my life.
هذا يعني بوضوح أنني سأخاطر بحياتي.
Aunt.
عمة.
I've heard that the personality of the young master of Xiqi
سمعت أن شخصية السيد الشاب في شي تشي
is even more terrifying.
بل إنه أمر مرعب للغاية.
To establish military authority,
لتأسيس السلطة العسكرية،
he often punishes people for minor offenses
كثيراً ما يعاقب الناس على المخالفات البسيطة
by cutting off their limbs.
بقطع أطرافهم.
Now I'm confined to the mansion,
أنا الآن محصور في القصر،
while Li holds all the power.
بينما يمتلك لي كل السلطة.
Even if I want to help you refuse,
حتى لو أردت مساعدتك على الرفض،
she won't listen to me.
إنها لا تستمع إليّ.
Aunt.
عمة.
Could it be that I truly have no choice
هل يعقل أنه ليس لدي خيار حقاً؟
but to be manipulated by her?
لكن أن يتم التلاعب بي من قبلها؟
In a few days,
في غضون أيام قليلة،
the Xiqi delegation will arrive,
سيصل وفد شي تشي،
and there will be no turning back.
ولن يكون هناك رجوع إلى الوراء.
Li's position
موقف لي
is not yet secure.
لم يتم تأمينه بعد.
The marriage alliance
تحالف الزواج
is for border stability.
يهدف ذلك إلى استقرار الحدود.
The young master of Xiqi is a brilliant talent
المعلم الشاب لفن شي تشي موهبة رائعة
who has never lost a battle.
الذي لم يخسر معركة قط.
In recent years, he has achieved numerous military victories
في السنوات الأخيرة، حقق العديد من الانتصارات العسكرية.
and has already become Mocheng's
وقد أصبح بالفعل ملكًا لموتشنغ
greatest threat.
أكبر تهديد.
You must not lose your manners
يجب ألا تفقد أدبك
or do anything outrageous.
أو القيام بأي شيء شائن.
A failed marriage alliance is the least of our concerns.
إن فشل تحالف الزواج هو أقل ما يقلقنا.
If it gives them an excuse to march on us,
إذا كان ذلك يمنحهم ذريعة للزحف علينا،
that's where the real trouble begins.
وهنا تبدأ المشكلة الحقيقية.
I will certainly behave well
سأتصرف بالتأكيد بشكل جيد
and make my dear sister
واجعل أختي العزيزة
proud.
فخور.
Good child.
طفل صالح.
Feng Li,
فنغ لي,
if you're heartless, don't blame me for being ruthless.
إذا كنت عديم الرحمة، فلا تلومني على قسوتي.
My wedding day
يوم زفافي
will be the day of your death.
سيكون يوم وفاتك.
You've delivered yourself right to me.
لقد سلمت نفسك لي مباشرة.
You just started serving that girl
لقد بدأت للتو في خدمة تلك الفتاة
and now you dare to come for my life.
والآن تجرؤ على المجيء لأخذ حياتي.
Slicing you into a thousand pieces would not be too cruel.
تقطيعك إلى ألف قطعة لن يكون قاسياً للغاية.
I want to see
أريد أن أرى
how she'll save you this time.
كيف ستنقذك هذه المرة.
For Her Majesty,
لجلالة الملكة،
I am willing to do anything.
أنا على استعداد لفعل أي شيء.
When we get to my palace,
عندما نصل إلى قصري،
you'd better still be
من الأفضل أن تبقى
as defiant as you are now.
بمثل هذا التحدي الذي أنت عليه الآن.
[Fengling Hall]
[قاعة فينغلينغ]
Look,
ينظر،
what nice little tool is this?
ما هذه الأداة الصغيرة اللطيفة؟
Tell me,
أخبرني،
which finger should I
أي إصبع يجب أن أستخدمه؟
start with?
بماذا نبدأ؟
Today,
اليوم،
I will tear you, the star
سأمزقك يا نجم
from Feng Li's heart.
من قلب فنغ لي.
Are you done with this nonsense?
هل سئمت من هذا الهراء؟
Greetings, Your Majesty.
تحية طيبة يا صاحب الجلالة.
He openly attempted to assassinate me.
لقد حاول اغتيالي علنًا.
For such a deranged person,
بالنسبة لشخص مختل عقلياً كهذا،
why shouldn't I impose punishment?
لماذا لا يحق لي فرض العقاب؟
You claim he attempted assassination,
تزعم أنه حاول اغتيالك،
but do you have evidence?
لكن هل لديك دليل؟
I am the evidence.
أنا الدليل.
I did not.
لم أفعل.
I merely
أنا فقط
met Princess Ling in the corridor.
قابلت الأميرة لينغ في الممر.
spoke well of Your Majesty.
تحدثت بشكل جيد عن جلالتكم.
She became angry from embarrassment
غضبت من شدة الإحراج.
and then had me brought here.
ثم أمروا بإحضاري إلى هنا.
What?
ماذا؟
You just insisted
لقد أصررتَ للتو
that you came to kill me because of her.
أنك جئت لقتلي بسببها.
Nonsense!
هراء!
If I wanted to kill you,
لو أردت قتلك،
why would I need someone else to do it?
لماذا أحتاج إلى شخص آخر ليقوم بذلك؟
Everyone here today witnessed
شهد الجميع هنا اليوم
that you kidnapped my man,
أنك اختطفت رجلي،
tortured him recklessly,
عذبوه بتهور،
and by law should be executed.
ويجب تنفيذه بموجب القانون.
Considering you'll be sent to Xiqi for a political marriage in a few days,
بما أنك ستُرسل إلى شي تشي لعقد زواج سياسي خلال أيام قليلة،
I'll spare you this time.
سأوفر عليك عناء ذلك هذه المرة.
If I hear more
إذا سمعت المزيد
of your gossiping rumors again,
من شائعاتك النميمة مجدداً،
that mouth of yours
فمك هذا
won't be needed anymore!
لن تكون هناك حاجة إليها بعد الآن!
From today on,
ابتداءً من اليوم،
you are confined here,
أنت محتجز هنا،
and no one may enter or leave.
ولا يجوز لأحد الدخول أو الخروج.
Violators will be executed.
سيتم إعدام المخالفين.
Yes, Your Majesty.
نعم يا جلالة الملك.
Feng Li!
فنغ لي!
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Your Majesty!
جلالتك!
Why is it you?
لماذا أنت بالذات؟
Where is Her Majesty?
أين جلالتها؟
Don't tell me
لا تخبرني
you expect Her Majesty
تتوقعون جلالتها
to serve you herself.
لخدمتك بنفسها.
Who do you think you are?
من تظن نفسك؟
How dare you treat me with such disrespect?
كيف تجرؤ على معاملتي بهذه القلة من الاحترام؟
Let me tell you,
دعني أخبرك،
I'm now Her Majesty's favorite person.
أنا الآن الشخص المفضل لدى جلالتها.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Her Majesty ordered me to serve you,
أمرتني جلالتها بخدمتكم،
her precious slave.
عبدها الثمين.
It depends on your performance.
الأمر يعتمد على أدائك.
If you serve me well,
إذا خدمتني جيداً،
I'll naturally put in
سأقوم بوضعها بشكل طبيعي
a good word for you with Her Majesty.
كلمة طيبة لك عند جلالة الملكة.
What are you standing there for?
لماذا تقف هناك؟
Get me some water.
أحضر لي بعض الماء.
Are you trying to let me die of thirst?
هل تحاول أن تتركني أموت من العطش؟
Where's my water?
أين مائي؟
How dare you! What are you doing?
كيف تجرؤ! ​​ماذا تفعل؟
I'll report this to Her Majesty!
سأبلغ جلالتها بهذا الأمر!
So thirsty?
هل تشعر بالعطش الشديد؟
Right.
يمين.
Her Majesty specifically instructed me
لقد أعطتني جلالتها تعليمات محددة
to take good care of you.
لأعتني بك جيداً.
So I'll
لذا سأفعل
feed you the water myself.
سأسقيك الماء بنفسي.
You...
أنت...
No!
لا!
Help!
يساعد!
Let me go!
دعني أذهب!
Today's tribute tea has pine fragrance.
يتميز شاي اليوم المخصص للتكريم برائحة الصنوبر.
Would you like to try it, Your Majesty?
هل ترغب في تجربته يا صاحب الجلالة؟
What happened to your hand?
ماذا حدث ليدك؟
The other day,
في اليوم الآخر،
I wanted to carve a jade seal for Your Majesty myself.
كنت أرغب في نحت ختم من اليشم لجلالتكم بنفسي.
The carving knife was sharp.
كانت سكين النحت حادة.
I was careless and cut myself.
كنت مهملاً وجرحت نفسي.
Does it hurt?
هل يؤلمك؟
It doesn't hurt.
لا يؤلم.
It's already healed.
لقد شفيت بالفعل.
You're always like this.
أنت دائماً هكذا.
You get injured
تتعرض للإصابة
and never tell me about it.
ولا تخبرني بذلك أبداً.
That day,
في ذلك اليوم،
I was a bit harsh with you.
كنت قاسياً بعض الشيء معك.
Are you still upset with me?
هل ما زلت غاضباً مني؟
How could I be upset with you?
كيف لي أن أغضب منك؟
I was overly concerned.
كنت قلقاً أكثر من اللازم.
There must be some special reason.
لا بد أن يكون هناك سبب خاص.
I should have trusted Your Majesty's resolve.
كان ينبغي عليّ أن أثق في عزم جلالتكم.
You're always so understanding.
أنت دائماً متفهم للغاية.
Actually, he resembles someone from my past.
في الحقيقة، إنه يشبه شخصاً من ماضيّ.
Is...
يكون...
Is he the boy you once mentioned
هل هو الصبي الذي ذكرته من قبل؟
who was with you in the wasteland
من كان معك في الأرض القاحلة
and survived together with you?
وهل نجوتما معاً؟
Yes.
نعم.
Fate is full of irony.
القدر مليء بالمفارقات.
I never expected to meet him again in the palace.
لم أتوقع أبداً أن أقابله مرة أخرى في القصر.
Then, Your Majesty,
ثم يا جلالة الملك،
how do you plan to arrange for this old friend?
كيف تخطط لترتيب لقاء هذا الصديق القديم؟
I'll have to think about it carefully.
سأضطر إلى التفكير في الأمر بعناية.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
This is by order of the Princess Royal of Mocheng.
هذا بأمر من الأميرة الملكية لموتشينغ.
This medicine
هذا الدواء
should be delivered to the Demon Lord by me.
يجب أن أقوم أنا بتسليمها إلى سيد الشياطين.
Your Highness!
يا صاحب السمو!
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Something's wrong.
هناك خطب ما.
Your Highness's pulse doesn’t feel right.
نبض سموكم ليس على ما يرام.
No wonder the Queen of Mocheng takes daily tonics
لا عجب أن ملكة موتشنغ تتناول المنشطات يومياً
laced with poison,
مسمومة،
yet shows no signs of poisoning.
ومع ذلك لا تظهر عليه أي علامات تسمم.
So those tonics
لذا فإن تلك المقويات
were all taken by Your Highness.
تم التقاطها جميعاً من قبل صاحب السمو.
This poison specifically targets the heart
يستهدف هذا السم القلب تحديداً
and is nearly impossible to counter.
ويكاد يكون من المستحيل مواجهته.
Your Highness, why would you do this?
يا صاحب السمو، لماذا تفعل هذا؟
I have my own plans.
لدي خططي الخاصة.
You need not concern yourself.
لا داعي للقلق.
Feng Li's life
حياة فنغ لي
is mine alone to take.
لي وحدي الحق في أخذه.
Your Highness!
يا صاحب السمو!
There's been a change of plans.
طرأ تغيير على الخطط.
Starting tonight,
ابتداءً من الليلة،
you will enter the palace as a court lady
ستدخلين القصر كإحدى سيدات البلاط.
and seize the opportunity to assassinate the Queen of Mocheng.
وانتهز الفرصة لاغتيال ملكة موتشينغ.
Be quick.
أسرع.
Yes.
نعم.
It's late at night with heavy dew.
الوقت متأخر من الليل والندى كثيف.
Court lady,
سيدة البلاط،
where are you going to serve now?
أين ستخدم الآن؟
I am a court lady in the palace
أنا سيدة البلاط في القصر
of the newly appointed Queen.
للملكة المعينة حديثاً.
I'm on my way to serve the Queen at Fengxi Palace.
أنا في طريقي لخدمة الملكة في قصر فينغشي.
Wandering around
التجول في الأنحاء
is against the rules.
مخالف للقواعد.
Fengxi Palace?
قصر فنغشي؟
Fengxi Palace is not exactly a place of good fortune.
قصر فينغشي ليس مكاناً يجلب الحظ السعيد بالضبط.
I advise you
أنصحك
not to set foot in that place.
عدم وضع قدمي في ذلك المكان.
I came here on orders
لقد جئت إلى هنا بناءً على أوامر.
and have no intention of giving up halfway.
وليس لديهم أي نية للاستسلام في منتصف الطريق.
Ruo!
حتى!
Your Highness has good eyes.
صاحب السمو يتمتع ببصر جيد.
Among General Lu's subordinates,
من بين مرؤوسي الجنرال لو،
you're the only one who can match me
أنت الوحيد الذي يستطيع مجاراتي
for a few moves, Ruo.
لبضع حركات، يا رو.
Unfortunately, Your Highness is unwell
للأسف، سموكم ليس على ما يرام
and may not be my match.
وقد لا يكون مناسباً لي.
The Xiqi delegation arrives in 3 days.
سيصل وفد شي تشي خلال ثلاثة أيام.
Once the marriage alliance is formed,
بمجرد تشكيل تحالف الزواج،
Dongli will have little chance to restore its kingdom.
لن يكون أمام دونغلي فرصة كبيرة لاستعادة مملكتها.
I came here
لقد أتيت إلى هنا
to assist Your Highness
لمساعدة سموكم
in killing the Demon Lord of Mocheng.
في قتل سيد الشياطين في موتشينغ.
Feng Li's life
حياة فنغ لي
is mine alone to take.
لي وحدي الحق في أخذه.
When and how to kill her
متى وكيف أقتلها؟
is not for any of you to interfere with.
ليس من حق أي منكم التدخل في ذلك.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
you can barely control your own life,
بالكاد تستطيع التحكم بحياتك،
how can you control others'?
كيف يمكنك السيطرة على الآخرين؟
If you still acknowledge me as your lord,
إذا كنت لا تزال تعترف بي سيداً لك،
get out now.
اخرج الآن.
This Yun Zhan
هذا يون زان
is truly despicable.
إنه أمر حقير حقاً.